BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
THE PEOPLE, GROUPS, PLACES, AND INCIDENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE PURELY FICTIONAL
الأشخاص والمجموعات والأماكن والحوادث في هذه الدراما خيالية حقًا
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
You must…
يجب عليك أن…
4 YEARS AGO
منذ 4 سنوات
…dethrone the Crown Prince!
… خلع ولي العهد!
-You must dethrone the Crown Prince!
-يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!  -يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!
The recklessness of His Royal Highness worsens day after day,
إن تهور صاحب السمو الملكي يتفاقم يوما بعد يوم ،
and his behavior is starting to break down our customs.
وقد بدأ سلوكه في تحطيم عاداتنا.
You must dethrone the Crown Prince
يجب خلع ولي العهد
and reinstate the foundation of our nation!
ونعيد تأسيس أمتنا!
-You must dethrone the Crown Prince
- يجب خلع ولي العهد - يجب خلع ولي العهد
-and reinstate our nation's foundation!
- وأعد تأسيس أمتنا!  - وأعد تأسيس أمتنا!
-You must dethrone the Crown Prince!
-يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!  -يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!
Three state councilors of the State Council,
ثلاثة من أعضاء مجالس الدولة بمجلس الدولة ،
then even Six Ministries and Three Offices joined in this protest.
ثم انضمت حتى ست وزارات وثلاثة مكاتب في هذا الاحتجاج.
That means the entire Royal Court is in this together.
هذا يعني أن الديوان الملكي بأكمله موجود في هذا معًا.
I can no longer protect you.
لم أعد أستطيع حمايتك.
You must…
يجب عليك أن…
survive on your own now.
البقاء على قيد الحياة بنفسك الآن.
I shall do that.
سأفعل ذلك.
Even if…
حتى لو…
I must rip my limbs out to survive, I shall survive.
يجب أن أمزق أطرافي من أجل البقاء على قيد الحياة ، وسأبقى على قيد الحياة.
-You must dethrone the Crown Prince!
-يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!  -يجب عليك خلع ولي العهد!
-You must dethrone the Crown Prince
- يجب خلع ولي العهد - يجب خلع ولي العهد
-and reinstate our nation's foundation!
- وأعد تأسيس أمتنا!  - وأعد تأسيس أمتنا!
I'll marry Lady Yoon, just as the Queen
سأتزوج السيدة يون ، تمامًا مثل الملكة
and the Royal Court decided.
وقرر الديوان الملكي.
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
a royal marriage is not something to be dealt with.
الزواج الملكي ليس بالشيء الذي يجب التعامل معه.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
what can I do?
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل؟
This foolish man does not understand what His Royal Highness means.
هذا الرجل الأحمق لا يفهم ماذا يعني صاحب السمو الملكي.
A subject can only give advice,
يمكن للموضوع تقديم المشورة فقط ،
and every decision is made by His Majesty.
وكل قرار يتخذ من قبل جلالة الملك.
What are you all doing?
ماذا تفعلون؟
Do you dare to look down on His Royal Highness?
هل تجرؤ على النظر باستخفاف صاحب السمو الملكي؟
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
You are the foundation of our nation.
أنتم أساس أمتنا.
How can you bow your head as our foundation?
كيف تحني رأسك كأساس لنا؟
How can you kneel down so easily
كيف يمكنك الركوع بهذه السهولة
The true foundation of Joseon…
الأساس الحقيقي لجوسون ...
are the nobles.
هم النبلاء.
I will not
لن أفعل
seek after the royal authority
السعي وراء السلطة الملكية
as the tyrant you deposed did.
كما فعل الطاغية الذي خلعته.
I will not hold you in check just as His Majesty does.
لن أضعك تحت المراقبة تمامًا كما يفعل جلالة الملك.
I will
أنا سوف
respect the words of the subjects and Three Offices…
احترم كلام الموضوعات والمكاتب الثلاثة ...
as the King.
كملك.
So please,
إذن من فضلك،
help me.
ساعدني.
BLOODY HEART EPISODE 1
قلب دموي الحلقة 1
QUEEN YOON
الملكة يون
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Get the royal physician!
احصل على الطبيب الملكي!
Now! Go!
حاليا!  يذهب!
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It has been four years since we waited for Her Majesty's conception.
لقد مرت أربع سنوات منذ أن انتظرنا تصور صاحبة الجلالة.
You should take in a royal concubine
يجب أن تأخذ في محظية ملكية
and have a son in your royal family.
ولديك ابن في عائلتك المالكة.
How can you be so impudent to the young Queen?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون وقحًا جدًا مع الملكة الشابة؟
She can always conceive a baby, even today.
يمكنها دائمًا أن تحمل طفلًا ، حتى اليوم.
Internal Prince, your loyalty as a subject comes first
أمير داخلي ، ولائك كموضوع يأتي أولاً
before your love for your daughter.
قبل حبك لابنتك.
Left Minister, you choose to overlook how His Majesty feels.
الوزير الأيسر ، اخترت التغاضي عن شعور جلالة الملك.
That means your ulterior motive came first!
هذا يعني أن دافعك الخفي جاء أولاً!
Otherwise, does Left State Councilor harbor an ulterior motive?
وإلا ، هل لدى عضو مجلس الدولة اليساري دافع خفي؟
Speak up.
تكلم.
Can you confidently say
هل يمكنك القول بثقة
this selection was done without ulterior motives?
هذا الاختيار تم بدون دوافع خفية؟
A subject can only give advice.
يمكن للموضوع تقديم النصيحة فقط.
When His Majesty gives an order,
عندما يأمر جلالة الملك ،
I simply honor and follow it.
أنا ببساطة أحترمها وأتبعها.
If the Queen requests it,
إذا طلبت الملكة ذلك ،
I shall allow you to select a royal concubine.
سأسمح لك باختيار محظية ملكية.
How?
كيف؟
How did you not have any idea
كيف لم يكن لديك أي فكرة
until Her Majesty was in such dire condition?
حتى كانت جلالة الملكة في مثل هذه الحالة الأليمة؟
Her Majesty said
قالت جلالة الملكة
she must keep clean while she has the pregnancy talisman on herself
يجب أن تحافظ على نظافتها أثناء حملها تعويذة الحمل على نفسها
-and did not allow me to feel her pulse. -I don't need excuses.
- ولم تسمح لي أن أشعر بنبضها.  -لست بحاجة إلى أعذار.
Who else knows other than you?
من غيرك يعرف غيرك؟
Nobody knows. I must relay this to the King's Palace.
لا أحد يعرف.  يجب أن أنقل هذا إلى قصر الملك.
What can His Majesty do at this point?
ماذا يمكن أن يفعل جلالة الملك في هذه المرحلة؟
The fate of the Yoon family depends upon this.
مصير عائلة يون يعتمد على هذا.
Yes, my lord.
نعم سيدي.
My arrow must have become nervous with you watching, Left State Councilor.
يجب أن يكون سهمي متوترًا وأنت تشاهد ، مستشار الدولة الأيسر.
Everyone knows that you are an excellent archer, Your Majesty.
يعلم الجميع أنك رامي ممتاز يا صاحب الجلالة.
I'm only afraid you will choose to train in martial arts
أخشى فقط أن تختار التدريب في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
and neglect your daily lessons.
وإهمال دروسك اليومية.
I'll remember your advice.
سأتذكر نصيحتك.
It is my honor.
إنه لشرف لي.
In that case, please allow me to give you another word of counsel.
في هذه الحالة ، اسمح لي أن أقدم لك نصيحة أخرى.
I understand you want a son from the Queen.
أفهم أنك تريد ابنًا من الملكة.
But as we cannot postpone this any longer,
ولكن بما أننا لا نستطيع تأجيل هذا أكثر من ذلك ،
it's the Queen Dowager's will for you to select a royal concubine.
إنها إرادة الملكة الأرملة أن تختار محظية ملكية.
I'll try to persuade the internal prince again--
سأحاول إقناع الأمير الداخلي مرة أخرى--
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Instead of persuading,
بدلا من الإقناع ،
give him an order.
أعطه أمرا.
I accept your advice.
أنا أقبل نصيحتك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Eunuch Jung of the Queen's Palace is here.
هنا الخصي جونغ من قصر الملكة.
I came to report that I found a site for a pavilion for Internal Prince.
جئت لأبلغ أنني وجدت موقعًا لجناحًا لـ Internal Prince.
I wanted to console the internal prince
كنت أرغب في مواساة الأمير الداخلي
by demolishing a deserted house and building a pavilion.
بهدم منزل مهجور وبناء سرادق.
How big is it?
كم حجمها؟
A house of 21 kan will be used to build it with 4 dan and 4 jum,
سيتم استخدام منزل من 21 كان لبناءه مع 4 دان و 4 جم ،
and a house of 22 kan will become 3 dan and 9 jum.
ومنزل من 22 كان سيصبح 3 دان و 9 جم.
Proceed.
يتابع.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
I must go visit the Queen.
يجب أن أذهب لزيارة الملكة.
My lord.
ربي.
This is absolutely urgent.
هذا أمر ملح للغاية.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The Queen's Palace is the other way.
قصر الملكة هو الطريق الآخر.
CLASSIC OF POETRY
كلاسيك في الشعر
QUEEN DOWAGER CHOI GAYEON
الملكة دوواجر تشوي جايون
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
Internal Prince has been waiting for half an hour.
الأمير الداخلي كان ينتظر لمدة نصف ساعة.
Has it been that long already?
هل مضى كل هذا الوقت بالفعل؟
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
نعم ، صاحب السمو الملكي.
Let him in after another quarter of an hour.
دعه يدخل بعد ربع ساعة أخرى.
Why haven't I heard from my father?
لماذا لم اسمع من والدي؟
How can he leave the Royal Court even after he heard that I fainted?
كيف يخرج من الديوان الملكي حتى بعد أن سمع أنني أغمي علي؟
The Queen is ill.
الملكة مريضة.
It is absurd that no one has come to visit me!
من السخف ألا يأتي أحد لزيارتي!
Internal Prince, what brings you here?
أمير داخلي ، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
I hear you are deeply concerned about the future generation
أسمع أنك قلق للغاية بشأن جيل المستقبل
of the royal family.
من العائلة المالكة.
It was extremely inscrutable and embarrassing.
كان الأمر غامضًا ومحرجًا للغاية.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
I heard you were against a concubine.
سمعت أنك ضد محظية.
How could I go against the Queen Dowager?
كيف يمكنني الذهاب ضد الملكة الأرملة؟
However, for the sake of the sickly Queen,
ومع ذلك ، من أجل الملكة المريضة ،
please let me have all authority over the selection of the concubine.
واسمحوا لي أن أمتلك كل الصلاحيات فيما يتعلق باختيار المحظية.
If you let me,
لو سمحت لي،
I will be as faithful to you as a dog and horse.
سأكون مخلصًا لك مثل كلب وحصان.
It looks like
يبدو
the rumors are true.
الشائعات صحيحة.
Remove the girl who caused anger to the Queen.
ابعد الفتاة التي أثارت غضب الملكة.
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
I may be powerless,
قد أكون عاجزًا ،
but the King is here to visit the Queen.
لكن الملك هنا لزيارة الملكة.
I heard the Royal Court clamored
سمعت صراخ الديوان الملكي
for you to select a concubine as soon as possible.
لتختار محظية في أسرع وقت ممكن.
My eyes are only on you.
عيناي عليك فقط.
Their clamor is hardly important.
صراخهم يكاد لا يكون مهما.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I must have hurt you
لابد أني قد آذيتك
because I was a queen who viciously threw temper tantrums.
لأنني كنت ملكة تسببت في نوبات غضب شرسة.
It's because I was spiteful.
هذا لأنني كنت حاقدًا.
I hated how you tried to have a girl from an ordinary family
كرهت كيف حاولت أن يكون لديك فتاة من عائلة عادية
as the Crown Princess instead of me.
بصفتي ولي العهد بدلاً مني.
If that girl had been alive, I would have had her killed.
لو كانت تلك الفتاة على قيد الحياة ، لكنت قتلت.
That is how much
هذا كم
I am in love with you.
أنا في حب معك.
This is…
هذا هو…
the first time you said you loved me, my queen.
في المرة الأولى التي قلت فيها أنك أحببتني يا ملكتي.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I'll give you an answer.
سأعطيك إجابة.
My queen.
ملكتي.
You'll die soon.
ستموت قريبا.
The ailment went into her lungs and she can't be saved, can she?
المرض دخل رئتيها ولا يمكن إنقاذها ، أليس كذلك؟
I thought you loved her dearly,
اعتقدت أنك أحببتها كثيرا ،
but the first thing you suggested is that he select a concubine?
لكن أول ما اقترحته هو اختيار محظية؟
Power must be more important to you than your own bloodline.
يجب أن تكون القوة بالنسبة لك أكثر أهمية من سلالتك.
That was an awful joke.
كانت تلك مزحة فظيعة.
Joking…
يمزح…
is what you had said.
هو ما قلته.
If you truly know what it's like to be in love,
إذا كنت تعرف حقًا شعور الحب ،
you wouldn't have dared to say the word.
لم تكن لتجرؤ على قول الكلمة.
No child in this world
لا طفل في هذا العالم
would be happy to be loved by the child of their mother's murderer.
سيكونون سعداء أن يحبه ابن قاتل أمهم.
I rose to the throne after marrying you.
صعدت إلى العرش بعد الزواج منك.
Once you die,
بمجرد أن تموت ،
I'll be able to marry a family that can become my support.
سأكون قادرًا على الزواج من عائلة يمكن أن تصبح دعمي.
As you are now, my queen…
كما أنت الآن يا ملكتي ...
you are dearest to me.
انت اعز عندي.
Your Majesty…
جلالة الملك ...
Left State Councilor, give me one more chance.
غادر مستشار الدولة ، أعطني فرصة أخرى.
My lord!
ربي!
Internal Prince will be dismissed for deceiving His Majesty,
سيتم فصل الأمير الداخلي لخداع جلالة الملك ،
and he'll be severely punished according to the crimes he committed.
وسيعاقب بشدة حسب الجرائم التي ارتكبها.
-Your order is our command.
-طلبك هو أمرنا.  -طلبك هو أمرنا.
Your Royal Highness, His Majesty must not know
صاحب السمو الملكي ، جلالة الملك يجب ألا يعرف
until another royal physician diagnoses her ailment.
حتى يقوم طبيب ملكي آخر بتشخيص مرضها.
Of course, he doesn't know.
بالطبع ، هو لا يعرف.
Everyone, from the Chief Eunuch to the court lady at the Queen's service,
الجميع ، من كبير الخصيان إلى سيدة البلاط في خدمة الملكة ،
and even the maids,
وحتى الخادمات ،
are your eyes and ears.
هي عيناك وأذنيك.
We may even control His Majesty's breaths.
قد نتحكم حتى في أنفاس جلالة الملك.
How would he find out unless you allow him to know?
كيف يكتشف ما لم تسمح له بمعرفة؟
Your Majesty the Queen!
جلالة الملكة!
Careful.
حذر.
All right.
حسنا.
BAMBOO GROVE VILLAGE
قرية بامبو جروف
-Let's go. -Okay.
-لنذهب.  -تمام.
-Come on. Careful. -My goodness.
-هيا.  حذر.  -رباه.
-Why are you all in a hurry? -Oh my, Jinsa Lim.
-لماذا أنتم جميعا في عجلة من أمرهم؟  -أوه يا جينسا ليم.
A young master from Imjin Valley
سيد شاب من وادي إمجين
came to ask for our young lady's hand.
جئت لأطلب يد سيدتنا الشابة.
We turned him down through the matchmaker twice,
رفضناه من خلال الخاطبة مرتين ،
then he showed up himself.
ثم ظهر بنفسه.
He must be infatuated with her.
يجب أن يكون مفتونًا بها.
It'll feel so empty once she gets married.
ستشعر بالفراغ الشديد بمجرد زواجها.
Our sadness isn't the problem.
حزننا ليس هو المشكلة.
We should let our young lady ride the flowery wedding litter.
يجب أن ندع سيدتنا الشابة تركب فضلات الزفاف المنمقة.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
لا تتقدم على نفسك.
My… My la…
بلدي ... لا ...
My lady, please marry me.
سيدتي ، يرجى الزواج مني.
I'll take first place in the state examination
سآخذ المركز الأول في امتحان الدولة
and turn you into the wife of a senior official.
وتحولك إلى زوجة مسؤول كبير.
Even if you're in love with another man,
حتى لو كنت في حالة حب مع رجل آخر ،
it's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
I'll wait.
سوف انتظر.
That smells nice.
تلك الرائحة لطيفة.
Gosh, the wait is tormenting.
يا إلهي ، الانتظار يعذب.
My goodness!
رباه!
Good grief.
حزن جيد.
I'm sorry, my lord.
أنا آسف يا مولاي.
I'm quite late.
أنا متأخر جدا.
No. I'm just grateful that you came.
لا. أنا ممتن فقط لأنك أتيت.
I didn't realize I'd be so late after visiting the government office.
لم أكن أدرك أنني سأكون متأخرًا جدًا بعد زيارة المكتب الحكومي.
The government office? What business does a girl have there?
المكتب الحكومي؟  ما العمل الذي تملكه الفتاة هناك؟
To donate my workshop to the village.
للتبرع بورشتي للقرية.
Why…
لماذا…
Why would you donate that?
لماذا تتبرع بذلك؟
I get that all of Jeolla knows you made a fortune
أفهم أن كل أعضاء جولا يعلمون أنك جمعت ثروة
in the bamboo box business, but--
في تجارة علب الخيزران ، ولكن--
I already split up the profit with the crafters, so I have nothing.
لقد قسمت الربح بالفعل مع الحرفيين ، لذلك ليس لدي أي شيء.
Are you saying…
هل تقول…
you're penniless?
أنت مفلس؟
Yes.
نعم.
Didn't you know?
الا تعلم؟
I've never seen such an idiotic girl!
أنا لم أر قط مثل هذه الفتاة الحمقاء!
Why would you give away that much money?
لماذا قد تتخلى عن هذا القدر من المال؟
I already promised I'd send silver to Hanyang!
لقد وعدت بالفعل بأنني سأرسل الفضة إلى Hanyang!
What now? How will you patch this up?
ماذا الان؟  كيف ستصلح هذا؟
-Darn it. -Young master.
-رتقها.  -المعلم الصغير.
You'll get in serious trouble if you hurt me in Bamboo Grove Village.
ستواجه مشكلة خطيرة إذا جرحتني في قرية بامبو جروف.
Is that so? How dare you lie to me?
هل هذا صحيح؟  كيف تجرؤ على الكذب علي؟
Look at this girl.
انظر الى هذه الفتاة.
Oh my.
يا بلادي.
You shouldn't be doing this here.
لا يجب أن تفعل هذا هنا.
You! How dare you lay a hand on her?
أنت!  كيف تجرؤ على مد يدها؟
Why would you talk it out?
لماذا تتحدث عنها؟
Our language is
لغتنا هي
this club.
هذا النادي.
How dare you try to hurt a nobleman…
كيف تجرؤ على محاولة إيذاء رجل نبيل ...
My goodness, this young master
يا إلهي ، هذا السيد الشاب
-just hit me on the head! -My goodness.
-ضربني على رأسي فقط!  -رباه.
-My gosh. -I didn't hit your head.
-يا إلهي.  لم أضرب رأسك.
Oh my, this young master just hit me in the stomach!
أوه ، هذا السيد الشاب ضربني في معدتي!
-I didn't hit your stomach. -I saw it myself.
-أنا لم أضرب معدتك.  -رأيته بنفسي.
Oh my, this young master is now about to break my arm!
يا إلهي ، هذا السيد الشاب على وشك كسر ذراعي!
-What now? -Enough! You need to stop.
-ماذا الان؟  -كافية!  أنت بحاجة إلى التوقف.
Okay, I'm leaving.
حسنًا ، سأرحل.
I'll leave.
سأرحل.
-Look at him go. -Oh my.
-نظروه يذهب.  -يا.
That young master is running away!
هذا السيد الشاب يهرب!
Look at that jerk.
انظر إلى هذا الأحمق.
-Are you all right, my lady? -Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير سيدتي؟  -هل انت بخير؟
-Yes. -My gosh.
-نعم.  -يا إلهي.
I'm absolutely fine.
أنا بخير تمامًا.
-That's good. -What about your stomach?
-هذا جيد.  -ماذا عن معدتك؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
He's fine. He's quite sturdy.
انه على ما يرام.  إنه قوي للغاية.
What a relief.
ما يريح.
After the national funeral, there will be a marriage ban.
بعد الجنازة الوطنية ، سيكون هناك حظر للزواج.
The noblemen who marry off their daughters before the ban
النبلاء الذين تزوجوا بناتهم قبل الحظر
and the ones who wait for the ban will
والذين ينتظرون الحظر سيفعلون
all require bamboo boxes for dowries.
كلها تتطلب صناديق من الخيزران للمهور.
Send someone to Hanyang and get a list of such people.
أرسل شخصًا إلى Hanyang واحصل على قائمة بهؤلاء الأشخاص.
-Yes.
-نعم.  -نعم.
Everyone, hurry.
الجميع ، على عجل.
I must leave for Hanyang before the marriage ban is instated.
يجب أن أغادر إلى هانيانغ قبل فرض حظر الزواج.
I'll return with a huge profit, so look forward to it.
سأعود بربح ضخم ، لذا نتطلع إليه.
Sounds great. Get us some powder when you come.
يبدو عظيما.  أحضر لنا بعض المسحوق عندما تأتي.
And some yeot from Hanyang.
وبعضكم من هانيانغ.
My kids love that.
أطفالي يحبون ذلك.
Okay, I'll get some powder, some yeot,
حسنًا ، سأحصل على بعض البودرة ، وبعضها ،
and even abduct a scholar to marry.
بل وخطف عالم للزواج.
Oh my.
يا بلادي.
So you really do have a scholar you like in Hanyang.
إذاً لديك حقًا عالم تحبه في هانيانغ.
Of course.
بالطبع.
I'll make sure to abduct him this time, so look forward to meeting him.
سأتأكد من اختطافه هذه المرة ، لذا تطلعوا لمقابلته.
All right.
حسنا.
My goodness, her.
يا إلهي لها.
You never forget to visit me although I'm your stepmother.
أنت لا تنسى زيارتى على الرغم من أنني زوجة أبيك.
Your devotion to your parents
إخلاصك لوالديك
sets an example for everyone.
يضع قدوة للجميع.
It is simply my duty as a son.
إنه ببساطة واجبي كإبن.
Have some.
لدينا بعض.
It's not poisoned.
انها ليست مسمومة.
It was a joke.
كانت مزحة.
I heard you still have trouble sleeping,
سمعت أنك ما زلت تواجه مشكلة في النوم ،
so I prepared chrysanthemum tea.
لذلك أعددت شاي الأقحوان.
The Queen died in such vain.
ماتت الملكة عبثا.
How could you sleep in peace?
كيف يمكنك أن تنام بسلام؟
Is this the second time?
هل هذه هي المرة الثانية؟
The Crown Princess died in vain too.
ماتت ولي العهد عبثا أيضا.
I heard that she was
سمعت أنها كانت كذلك
burnt beyond recognition.
محترقة لا يمكن التعرف عليها.
Allow me to tell you this since this is a national funeral.
اسمح لي أن أخبرك بهذا لأن هذه جنازة وطنية.
The Queen's Palace cannot be left vacant for long.
لا يمكن ترك قصر الملكة شاغرا لفترة طويلة.
Everyone is
كل شخص هو
on the Left State Councilor's side.
على الجانب الأيسر من مجلس الدولة.
Your Majesty, the weather is still cold.
جلالة الملك ، الجو لا يزال باردا.
I don't think I'll be falling asleep easily tonight.
لا أعتقد أنني سأنام بسهولة الليلة.
I'll sleep at the library.
سأنام في المكتبة.
Yes, I will get the place ready.
نعم ، سأجهز المكان.
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
7 YEARS AGO
قبل 7 سنوات
You must return to the palace.
يجب أن تعود إلى القصر.
It's my marriage.
إنه زواجي.
I need to see Lady Yoon's looks and character myself to decide
أحتاج إلى رؤية مظهر وشخصية السيدة يون بنفسي لأقرر
if she is suitable as a crown princess.
إذا كانت مناسبة لتاج الأميرة.
It's not too late to go back to the palace.
لم يفت الأوان بعد للعودة إلى القصر.
I'll tell the bodyguards to escort you back.
سأقول للحراس الشخصيين أن يرافقوك مرة أخرى.
Young master!
المعلم الصغير!
Young master?
المعلم الصغير؟
Come and take a look!
وتعالوا نلقي نظرة!
-Come and look. -Open for business.
-تأتي والبحث.  -مفتوح للعمل.
Come and get your powder.
تعال واحصل على مسحوقك.
Run!
يجري!
If we just bring you eggs,
إذا أحضرنا لك البيض فقط ،
you'll really turn them into chicks? Even without a chicken?
هل ستحولهم حقًا إلى كتاكيت؟  حتى بدون دجاجة؟
Of course. Put them in there.
بالطبع.  ضعهم هناك.
Good.
جيد.
Okay.
تمام.
That's enough moisture.
هذه رطوبة كافية.
Thankfully, the weather is nice.
لحسن الحظ ، الجو لطيف.
Don't forget to turn them around three times a day.
لا تنسى أن تقلبهم ثلاث مرات في اليوم.
Wait just three, four days, and you'll see chicks here.
انتظر ثلاثة أو أربعة أيام فقط وسترى الكتاكيت هنا.
A young girl is here deceiving foolish people.
فتاة صغيرة هنا تخدع الحمقى.
What has the world come to?
إلى ماذا جاء العالم؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Do you really believe the egg will hatch without a chicken to brood them?
هل تعتقد حقًا أن البيضة سوف تفقس بدون دجاجة لتفقسها؟
Yes, once you create a warm, moist environment as if a hen were there.
نعم ، بمجرد إنشاء بيئة دافئة ورطبة كما لو كانت هناك دجاجة.
I saw the eggs hatch with my own two eyes.
رأيت البيض يفقس بأم عينيّ.
They won't hatch.
لن يفقسوا.
They can.
يستطيعون.
-They can too!
-يمكنهم أيضًا!  -يمكنهم أيضًا!
-My egg! -That's my egg!
-بيضتي!  -هذه بيضتي!
And now, it really won't hatch.
والآن ، لن يفقس حقًا.
-My egg is broken. -Enough!
- بيضتي مكسورة.  -كافية!
Instead,
في حين أن،
if you promise me that you won't fall for her deceit again,
إذا وعدتني أنك لن تقع في خداعها مرة أخرى ،
-I'll give you an egg each. -The eggs you just broke
-سأعطيك كل بيضة.  -البيض الذي كسرته للتو
weren't just eggs, but those were to become chickens.
لم تكن مجرد بيض ، لكنها أصبحت دجاجات.
Pay them back with the price of a chicken.
سدد لهم ثمن الدجاجة.
If you want the money, you can try to catch me.
إذا كنت تريد المال ، يمكنك محاولة الإمساك بي.
Giddyup!
جيديوب!
You can ride a horse?
يمكنك ركوب الحصان؟
You followed me all the way here just to get paid for the chickens?
لقد تابعتني طوال الطريق هنا فقط لتحصل على أجر مقابل الدجاج؟
Those eggs could have taught them
كان من الممكن أن يعلمهم هؤلاء البيض
that making an effort today could make tomorrow better.
أن بذل جهد اليوم يمكن أن يجعل الغد أفضل.
That's what you broke.
هذا ما كسرته.
Do you think I'll fall for some lie you made up for children?
هل تعتقد أنني سأقع في كذبة اختلقتها من أجل الأطفال؟
You'll fall into a swamp if you go that way.
سوف تسقط في مستنقع إذا ذهبت بهذه الطريقة.
Another lie.
كذبة أخرى.
You weren't lying.
لم تكن تكذب.
I do not lie.
انا لا اكذب.
Over there.
هناك.
That's where the women come to ride the swing on the Dano holiday.
هذا هو المكان الذي تأتي فيه النساء لركوب الأرجوحة في عطلة دانو.
I heard that many men come to see their fiancée before their marriage.
سمعت أن الكثير من الرجال يأتون لرؤية خطيبتهم قبل زواجهما.
It was true.
لقد كان صحيحا.
Then I'll trust that you'll leave the cost of the chickens at the tavern.
ثم سأثق أنك ستترك تكلفة الدجاج في الحانة.
Do you really believe you can hatch those eggs?
هل تعتقد حقًا أنه يمكنك فقس تلك البيض؟
Those kids only want to eat today.
هؤلاء الأطفال يريدون تناول الطعام اليوم فقط.
They'll eat the egg even before it hatches.
سوف يأكلون البيضة حتى قبل أن تفقس.
But still,
لكن مازال،
if they regret what they do, they'll learn something.
إذا ندموا على ما يفعلونه ، فسوف يتعلمون شيئًا ما.
Then next time, and the time after that, they would be a little better.
ثم في المرة القادمة ، وفي المرة التالية ، سيكونون أفضل قليلاً.
You are quite ugly.
أنت قبيح جدا.
You're ugly, cheeky,
أنت قبيح ، وقح ،
proud, and even vicious.
فخور ، وحتى شرير.
You talk a lot and aren't gentle,
أنت تتحدث كثيرًا ولست لطيفًا ،
so who'll ever marry you?
إذن من سيتزوجك؟
You're harsh.
أنت قاسي.
That's why…
لهذا…
I'll marry you.
سوف أتزوجك.
Chase her immediately.
طاردها على الفور.
Find out which family she's from,
تعرف على العائلة التي تنتمي إليها ،
her mother's family, and their reputation.
أهل والدتها وسمعتهم.
-Scholar Yoo Haksoo's daughter? -Yes.
ابنة العالِم يو هاكسو؟  -نعم.
I will not marry anybody else other than the daughter from that family.
لن أتزوج أي شخص آخر غير ابنة تلك العائلة.
Don't you know who Scholar Yoo Haksoo is?
ألا تعرف من هو الباحث يو هاكسو؟
He's known as the future of the Sarim.
وهو معروف بمستقبل صريم.
He's highly respected in the Sarim faction,
يحظى باحترام كبير في فصيل صريم ،
so the officials also keep him in check.
لذلك يبقيه المسؤولون أيضًا تحت المراقبة.
That is why.
لذلك.
We must increase the power of the Sarim to fight against the officials.
يجب أن نزيد من قوة الصارم لمحاربة المسؤولين.
Crown Prince.
ولي العهد.
Everyone, leave the room.
الجميع ، غادر الغرفة.
How can you be so reckless?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون متهور جدا؟
I told you that you must always stay alert in the palace.
أخبرتك أنه يجب أن تبقى دائمًا في حالة تأهب في القصر.
I apologize.
أنا أعتذر.
However,
لكن،
you also feel the same way as I do.
أنت أيضًا تشعر بنفس الطريقة التي أشعر بها.
You couldn't take the daughter of an official as a crown princess.
لا يمكنك أن تأخذ ابنة مسؤول كأميرة.
That's why you've put off my marriage until now.
لهذا السبب قمت بتأجيل زواجي حتى الآن.
Also,
ايضا،
she really is a good woman.
إنها حقًا امرأة جيدة.
She's kind and wise,
انها لطيفة وحكيمة
just as a queen should be.
كما يجب أن تكون الملكة.
I understand how you feel.
أنا أفهم شعورك.
It's time for your lecture, so you should go.
حان وقت محاضرتك ، لذا يجب أن تذهب.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The Crown Prince is right.
إن ولي العهد على حق.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
But I am still afraid.
لكني ما زلت خائفة.
I was enthroned by the selection of the officials
توجت باختيار المسؤولين
who deposed my older brother.
الذي خلع أخي الأكبر.
If I get the Sarim involved to keep the officials in check,
إذا قمت بإشراك الصريم لإبقاء المسؤولين تحت المراقبة ،
how will they respond?
كيف سيردون؟
On the day of their uprising,
يوم انتفاضتهم ،
my family was annihilated
تم القضاء على عائلتي
as the closest people of the dethroned king.
كأقرب شعب للملك المخلوع.
They gave you pressure to throw me out,
لقد ضغطوا عليك لتطردني ،
that they wouldn't serve a queen from a traitor's family.
أنهم لن يخدموا ملكة من عائلة الخائن.
But you overcame that pressure, putting your life at stake.
لكنك تغلبت على هذا الضغط ، ووضعت حياتك على المحك.
I am your husband.
أنا زوجك.
If I'm unable to protect my own wife,
إذا كنت غير قادر على حماية زوجتي ،
how could I keep this nation together?
كيف لي ان ابقي هذه الامة معا؟
In that case, trust the Crown Prince.
في هذه الحالة ، ثق في ولي العهد.
He's your successor.
إنه خليفتك.
"Get the Sarim involved
"أشركوا الصارم
to keep the officials of the coup in check."
للسيطرة على مسؤولي الانقلاب ".
That's what
وهذا ما
the Crown Prince said?
قال ولي العهد؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I, Scholar Yoo Haksoo, have come to your call.
أنا الباحث يو هاكسو ، جئت إلى مكالمتك.
I'd like to ask for your help.
أود أن أطلب مساعدتك.
I will lay down my life to carry out your order, Your Majesty.
سأبذل حياتي لتنفيذ أمرك ، جلالة الملك.
I'd like to have your daughter as the Crown Princess.
أود أن تكون ابنتك ولي العهد.
You're home.
أنت في المنزل.
You're here, Father.
أنت هنا يا أبي.
EXPANDED MEANING OF THE GREAT LEARNING
المعنى الموسع للتعلم العظيم
My dear, can you fetch me a bowl of honey water?
عزيزي هل يمكنك إحضار وعاء من العسل والمياه؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Someone asked for your hand.
طلب شخص ما يدك.
I guess there was a family that hasn't heard of me.
أعتقد أنه كانت هناك عائلة لم تسمع بي.
It would be the biggest honor, but also…
سيكون أكبر شرف ، ولكن أيضًا ...
the greatest responsibility.
أعظم مسؤولية.
Is it a royal marriage?
هل هو زواج ملكي؟
His Majesty is
جلالة الملك
trying to hold the officials in check by using the Sarim.
في محاولة للسيطرة على المسؤولين باستخدام الصارم.
Did you accept it?
هل قبلته
I should refuse it as a father,
يجب أن أرفضها كأب ،
but as a subject,
ولكن كموضوع ،
I must accept it.
يجب أن أقبلها.
Father, I don't want to live in the palace.
أبي ، لا أريد أن أعيش في القصر.
Were you not astonished
ألم تندهش
that so many have forgotten the people were the foundation of our nation?
أن كثيرين نسوا أن الشعب كان أساس أمتنا؟
In Joseon, the only place where a woman can use her studies for her country
في جوسون ، المكان الوحيد الذي يمكن للمرأة أن تستخدم فيه دراستها لبلدها
is life as the Queen.
هي الحياة كملكة.
I have not seen anyone
أنا لم أر أحدا
who could be a better queen
من يمكن أن تكون ملكة أفضل
than you.
منك.
If you fancy any of the ladies, let me know whenever you wish.
إذا كنت تتخيل أيًا من السيدات ، فأخبرني متى شئت.
I'm not going to meet them.
لن أقابلهم.
I want to watch her fall over in shock on our first night together.
أريد أن أشاهدها وهي تسقط في صدمة في أول ليلة لنا معًا.
She will most certainly scream.
بالتأكيد سوف تصرخ.
Please come in.
تفضل بالدخول.
This is where you'll stay from now on as the Crown Princess.
هذا هو المكان الذي ستبقى فيه من الآن فصاعدًا بصفتك ولي العهد.
All right.
حسنا.
The daughter of Scholar Yoo Haksoo was selected after all.
تم اختيار ابنة الباحث يو هاكسو بعد كل شيء.
This is to hold us in check by using the Sarim.
هذا لتقييدنا باستخدام الصارم.
I'd rather switch the King
أفضل تبديل الملك
than live to see that happen.
من العيش لرؤية ذلك يحدث.
One reformation makes us contributors to the country,
إصلاح واحد يجعلنا مساهمين في البلد ،
but two reformations make us traitors.
لكن اثنين من الإصلاحات تجعلنا خونة.
Then do you suggest we all lay down our lives?
إذن هل تقترح علينا جميعًا أن نضع حياتنا؟
The Queen is already an enemy,
الملكة هي بالفعل عدو ،
and now the Crown Princess is with the Sarim!
والآن ولي العهد مع صارم!
His Majesty
جلالته
just gave us a reason.
فقط أعطانا سبب.
Queen Shin is the daughter of the subject of the deposed king we killed,
الملكة شين هي ابنة موضوع الملك المخلوع الذي قتلناه ،
Shin Heogyeon.
شين هيوجيون.
And Scholar Yoo Haksoo studied with Shin Heogyeon, didn't he?
والباحث يو هاكسو درس مع شين هيوجيون ، أليس كذلك؟
No…
رقم…
Why are you taking him?
لماذا تأخذه؟
-Oh no. -Let's go!
-أوه لا.  -لنذهب!
-No, don't take him! -Move it!
-لا ، لا تأخذه!  -حركه!
Now!
حاليا!
I, Left State Councilor Park Gyewon,
أنا ، عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر بارك جيون ،
lay down my office,
أضع مكتبي ،
lay down my life, to inform you of this atrocity.
أضع حياتي لأبلغكم بهذه الفظائع.
Scholar Yoo Haksoo
الباحث يو هاكسو
abused his influence over the Sarim to plot treason!
استغل نفوذه على الصارم لتخطيط الخيانة!
The traitors who sided with him confessed everything
اعترف الخونة الذين وقفوا معه بكل شيء
and his crimes have been already exposed in detail.
وقد تم الكشف بالفعل عن جرائمه بالتفصيل.
What's more disastrous is
ما هو أكثر كارثية
how the traitors singled out the leader…
كيف خص الخونة القائد ...
as Her Majesty the Queen.
بصفتها صاحبة الجلالة الملكة.
The Queen harbored a grudge
كان لدى الملكة ضغينة
for the beheading of her father, Shin Heogyeon the traitor,
بقطع رأس والدها شين هيوجيون الخائن ،
and conspired to murder Your Majesty.
وتآمر لقتل جلالتك.
She conspired with the wicked Scholar Yoo Haksoo
تآمرت مع العالم الشرير يو هاكسو
to enthrone the Crown Prince for her regency.
لتتويج ولي العهد لوصايتها.
Everything came into the light through this incident.
ظهر كل شيء من خلال هذا الحادث.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Depose the Queen…
خلع الملكة ...
and expose
وفضح
every single crime she has committed!
كل جريمة ارتكبتها!
Left State Councilor.
عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر.
I ask of you.
انا اسأل عنك.
Please do not dethrone the Queen.
من فضلك لا تخلع الملكة.
She is
هي تكون
my wife.
زوجتي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You cannot bring…
لا يمكنك إحضار ...
personal feelings into a state matter.
المشاعر الشخصية في الدولة.
Palace Guards, imprison Left State Councilor immediately.
حراس القصر ، سجنوا مستشار الدولة على الفور.
He is a sinner who dare slander the Queen!
إنه عاص يجرؤ على افتراء الملكة!
What are the guards doing?
ماذا يفعل الحراس؟
Why is the commandant standing still?
لماذا القائد لا يزال قائما؟
You'll lay down your offices?
ستضع مكاتبك؟
Do you dare to threaten me?
هل تجرؤ على تهديدي؟
Palace Guards, lift up your swords!
حراس القصر ، ارفعوا سيوفكم!
Subjects,
المواضيع،
put your hats back on!
ضع قبعاتك مرة أخرى!
Do you regret it?
هل انت نادم على ذلك؟
No.
رقم.
Unless I chose one of their daughters,
إلا إذا اخترت إحدى بناتهم ،
they would have protested no matter who it was.
كانوا سيحتجون بغض النظر عمن كان.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
So make sure you protect the Crown Princess as her husband.
لذا تأكد من حماية ولي العهد كزوجها.
Just as my father did.
تماما كما فعل والدي.
Yes.
نعم.
A husband must protect his wife,
يجب على الزوج حماية زوجته ،
and a mother must protect her children.
ويجب على الأم حماية أطفالها.
Your tea is getting cold.
الشاي الخاص بك يبرد.
Tae.
تاي.
Yes,
نعم،
Mother?
الأم؟
I just
أنا فقط
poisoned your tea.
تسمم الشاي الخاص بك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I'll give you a reason to fight against them.
سأعطيك سببا للقتال ضدهم.
Your Majesty, please keep the Crown Prince safe.
جلالة الملك ، من فضلك حافظ على سلامة ولي العهد.
It's more than how much you usually took every day.
إنها أكثر من الكمية التي تتناولها عادة كل يوم.
You'll be sick for a few days.
ستمرض لبضعة أيام.
The Crown Prince of this nation was almost killed,
كاد ولي عهد هذه الأمة أن يقتل ،
so they'll play it safe for a while.
لذلك سوف يلعبونها بأمان لفترة من الوقت.
Left State Councilor
عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر
won't back down over such an obvious trick.
لن يتراجع عن مثل هذه الحيلة الواضحة.
He'll try even harder to depose you.
سيحاول جاهدًا إقالتك.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
A few sick days you suffer won't put an end to this.
بضعة أيام مرضية تعانيها لن تضع حدًا لهذا الأمر.
Crown Prince.
ولي العهد.
Your mother
والدتك
will not become a deposed queen.
لن تصبح ملكة مخلوعة.
I will die as the Queen of this country.
سأموت بصفتي ملكة هذا البلد.
Mother.
الأم.
I have been poisoned to death
لقد تسممت حتى الموت
with you, Crown Prince.
معك يا ولي العهد.
Remember that for life…
تذكر ذلك مدى الحياة ...
and make use of it.
والاستفادة منه.
The only thing that'll keep you safe
الشيء الوحيد الذي سيحافظ على سلامتك
is the sympathy people will have for you
هو التعاطف الذي سيحظى به الناس لك
as a child of a poisoned mother.
كطفل لأم مسمومة.
Is anybody out there?
هل من احد هناك؟
The Queen and the Crown Prince were poisoned.
تم تسميم الملكة وولي العهد.
Shut every palace gate!
أغلق كل بوابة قصر!
I will make sure I catch the criminal
سوف أتأكد من القبض على المجرم
and annihilate three generations to punish them for this crime!
وتقضي على ثلاثة أجيال لمعاقبتهم على هذه الجريمة!
What happened to those
ماذا حدث لهؤلاء
who caused Mother's death?
من تسبب في وفاة الأم؟
You must have cut off the limbs of Left State Councilor and the officials
لابد أنك قمت بقطع أطراف عضو مجلس الدولة اليساري والمسؤولين
and wiped out their families too.
وقضوا على عائلاتهم أيضًا.
I'm sure you had Mother's revenge.
أنا متأكد من أنك حصلت على انتقام الأم.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Left State Councilor is at your service.
مستشار الدولة الأيسر في خدمتك.
Why is he still in the palace?
لماذا لا يزال في القصر؟
He promised to preserve your life.
لقد وعد بالحفاظ على حياتك.
The Queen of this nation was poisoned to death.
ملكة هذه الأمة ماتت مسموما.
Why is the cause of this crime still not punished?
لماذا لم يعاقب سبب هذه الجريمة حتى الآن؟
How come nobody took responsibility?
كيف لا أحد يتحمل المسؤولية؟
Let the Left State Councilor in.
دعوا مستشار الدولة اليساري.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Yoo Haksoo, the traitor who murdered the Queen,
يو هاكسو ، الخائن الذي قتل الملكة ،
and his family were beheaded, and their fortune was confiscated.
وقد قُطعت رؤوس عائلته وصودرت ثرواتهم.
Please order the punishment of Yoo Haksoo's daughter.
الرجاء الأمر بمعاقبة ابنة يو هاكسو.
Left State Councilor!
عضو مجلس الدولة اليسار!
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
I'll tear you to pieces!
سأمزقك إربا!
-I'll kill you! -Shut his mouth
-سأقتلك!  -اغلق فمه
and lock him in his quarters!
وحبسه في مسكنه!
Let go of me. Let go.
ترك لي.  اتركه.
Yoo Haksoo's daughter is the daughter to a traitor.
ابنة يو هاكسو هي ابنة خائن.
Behead her tomorrow.
اقطع رأسها غدا.
Your order
طلبك
will be carried out.
سيتم تنفيذها.
Father.
أب.
-Mother. -Jung.
-الأم.  -جونغ.
-Let's go! -Father!
-لنذهب!  -أب!
Father! Mother!
أب!  الأم!
Mother! Father!
الأم!  أب!
TRAITOR YOO HAKSOO
الخائن يو هاكسو
Please spare
من فضلك تجنيب
Yoo Haksoo's daughter.
ابنة يو هاكسو.
That woman is innocent.
تلك المرأة بريئة.
Did the Queen die
هل ماتت الملكة
because she was guilty?
لأنها كانت مذنبة؟
I lost my wife because I am weak.
لقد فقدت زوجتي لأنني ضعيف.
Even after losing her, I have to protect you, Crown Prince.
حتى بعد أن فقدتها ، علي أن أحميك يا ولي العهد.
I am…
انا…
a cowardly husband who looks away from my wife's death.
زوج جبان يبتعد عن موت زوجتي.
Are you saying…
هل تقول…
I should also become a coward like you?
أنا أيضا يجب أن أصبح جبانا مثلك؟
I cannot do that.
لا أستطيع فعل هذا.
In the palace, there is a secret passage only known to successors of the throne.
يوجد في القصر ممر سري لا يعرفه إلا خلفاء العرش.
You can go out of the palace through this passage.
يمكنك الخروج من القصر عبر هذا الممر.
Follow Kyun.
اتبع كيون.
Go
يذهب
and prove that you are different from me.
وتثبت أنك مختلف عني.
When a man with a mask comes,
عندما يأتي رجل بقناع ،
he'll take you to a safe place.
سيأخذك إلى مكان آمن.
Once I go there,
بمجرد أن أذهب إلى هناك ،
will I see my mother and father?
هل سأرى أمي وأبي؟
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
They were beheaded…
تم قطع رؤوسهم ...
because I became the Crown Princess.
لأنني أصبحت ولي العهد.
But only I survived.
لكني فقط نجوت.
Why didn't you just leave me to die?
لماذا لم تتركني فقط لأموت؟
Please live.
يرجى العيش.
Because of me,
بسببي،
my mother passed away.
توفيت والدتي.
a family was wiped out.
تم القضاء على عائلة.
Even so, I will live.
ومع ذلك ، سأعيش.
I'll live
سوف أعيش
and torture
والتعذيب
the ones who slaughtered my mother and those dear to me.
الذين ذبحوا أمي وأولئك الأعزاء عليّ.
So please, stay alive.
لذا من فضلك ، ابق على قيد الحياة.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Please live and endure.
يرجى العيش والتحمل.
Thank you
شكرًا لك
for staying alive.
للبقاء على قيد الحياة.
My love who was ruined because of me,
حبي الذي خرب بسببي
my beloved
محبوبي
Crown Princess.
الأميرة المتوجة.
BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
Will you accept this?
هل تقبل هذا؟
Miss, do you really like a man like him?
آنسة ، هل تحبين حقا رجل مثله؟
You said he wouldn't tell you where he lives and what he does.
قلت إنه لن يخبرك أين يعيش وماذا يفعل.
Before the marriage ban,
قبل حظر الزواج ،
the Queen Dowager and Left State Councilor will decide on the Queen.
الملكة الأرملة وعضو مجلس الدولة اليساري سوف يقررون الملكة.
I'm going to select my niece as the Queen.
سأختار ابنة أخي لتكون الملكة.
What shall I do for you?
ماذا علي أن أفعل من أجلك؟
Why won't you let me meet the scholar?
لماذا لا تسمح لي بلقاء العالم؟
You don't know who he is.
أنت لا تعرف من هو.
I've told you, you'll fall in danger if you get closer to him.
لقد أخبرتك ، ستقع في خطر إذا اقتربت منه.
This is the beginning.
هذه البداية.
I cannot let the niece of Left State Councilor become the Queen.
لا أستطيع أن أسمح لابنة أخت عضو مجلس الدولة اليساري بأن تصبح ملكة.
Translated by Eun-sook Yoon
ترجمه أون سوك يون